A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1971-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1971-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.742
This collection consists of 32,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 22 August 1974.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1971-1972; University committees files, 1971-1972; and, special files regarding appreciation letters to students, 1971.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1971-1972, Boxes 1-56
SERIES II: University Committees, 1971-1972, Boxes 56-62
SERIES III: Special File - Appreciation Letters to Students, Box 63
Contents List
- Series I: General Files, 1971-1972
  - "A - Al" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - "A - H" 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - "J - Z" 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Reports 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Reports 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Admissions - Policy Governing Applicants with Records Showing Honor Violations (Permanent) 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Admission of Women 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Air Force - General (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Air Force Academy (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Air Force - ROTC 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - General 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Medical 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Charlottesville, Albemarle 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Franklin 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Kansas City 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - New York 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Richmond 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Tidewater 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Washington 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Day 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Fund 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Fund Annual Report 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Fund Meeting 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - American Association of University Professors 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - American Council on Education 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - American Council on Education - Newsletter 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Applications for positions "A - L" 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Applications for positions "M - Z" 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Architecture - General 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Architecture - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Army - General 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Army - ROTC 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Art 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Art - Bayly Museum 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Art - Museum of Fine Arts 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Art - Graduate Institute History of Art in Washington (Folder) 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Art Commission 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Asian Studies Consortium 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Colleges 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Universities 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Association of American Universities - Membership Committee 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Astronomy 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - General 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - Football 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - ACC 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Basketball 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Finance 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Flag Issue, Duke game - 25 September 1971 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Football Invitations 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Football, Navy - 11 September 1971 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Football, Duke - 25 September 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football, Vanderbilt - 2 October 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football, North Carolina State - 30 October 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football, V. P. I. - 6 November 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football, University of North Carolina - 13 November 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football, Maryland - 20 November 1971 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - 3-2-2 Committee (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Rowing Team 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Atlantic Council of the U. S. 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Attorney General (State) 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Audit Reports 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - "B - Bm" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - "Bn - Bz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Biology - General 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Audit report through June 1969 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Capital Outlay 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Director's Office 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Budget - General 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Budget - Miscellaneous information 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Bursar 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Business and Finance 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Business Manager 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Calendar of Events 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Cavalier Daily 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Center for Advanced Studies 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Center for Study Science, Technology and Public Policy 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Chemistry - General 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Civil Defense 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Civil Rights 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Classics 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Advisory Committee 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Building Program 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - General 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - College Entrance Examination Board 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Commerce 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Community Colleges 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Comptroller 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Comptroller (State) 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Computer Center 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Council of Presidents Special Reports - Pat Perkinson 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Council of Presidents 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Council of Presidents (Special File) 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Counselor to President for Special Development 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Council of Southern Universities (See also Southern Fellowship Fund) 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Counseling Center 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - "Da - De" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - "Df - Dz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Danforth Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Darlington School - Trustees 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Data Processing 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Degrees 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Development 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Ditchley Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - "E: Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Economics 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Education - General 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Education - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Educational TV 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Endowment Fund 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Engineering 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Engineering and Buildings (State) 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - English 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Enrollment 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Environmental Sciences 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - Faculty - General 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "A - Z" 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Orientation 1971-1972 (Box 19)
  - Faculty Committees 1971-1972 (Box 20)
  - Federal Executive Institute 1971-1972 (Box 20)
  - Federal Executive Institute - National Advisory Board 1971-1972 (Box 20)
  - Federal Executive Institute - Publications, reports, etc. 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - General 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Dupont 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Fine Arts Center 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - French Language and Literature and General Linguistics 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Finals - 1972 1971-1972 (Box 22)
  - Founder's Day - 1972 1971-1972 (Box 23)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - General Assembly 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - General Studies - General 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - General Studies - School of General Studies, Central Virginia Center 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - General Studies - Virginia High School League 1971-1972 (Box 24)
  - General Studies - University of Virginia Center for Continuing Education 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - George Mason College 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - George Mason College - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - Gifts and Grants Correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Governor's Office 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Governor's Advisory Board 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Governor's Management Study 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Graduate Business Sponsors 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Harvard Graduate Society Council 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act of 1971 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 - Title I 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act - Title II (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act - Title III (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act - Title IV (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act - Title V (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Higher Education Act - Title VI (Folder Empty) 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Highway Department 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - History 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Honors Program 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Honors System and Honor Committee 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Housing 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Information Services 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Institute of Government 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Institutional Analysis 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Institutional Analysis - Statistical Information: University of Virginia, November 19711971-1972 (Box 30)
  - International Students 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Intramural Department 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "A" 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "B" 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "C" 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "D" 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "E" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "F" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "G" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "H" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "I" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "J" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "K" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "L" (folder empty) 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "M" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "N" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "O" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "P" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "R" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "S" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "T" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "U" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "V" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "W" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "X" (folder empty) 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "Y" 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Invitations - "Z" (folder empty) 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Minutes 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Monthly reports 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Jefferson Society 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Judiciary Committee 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - Law - General 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - Law - Admissions, "A - Z" 1971-1972 (Box 33)
  - Law - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Law Enforcement Education Program (LEEP) 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Lecturers 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Legal Adviser 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Legal - Estates 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Library - General 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Library Associates 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Library Resources Council 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - McConnell Award 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - The Mount Vernon Ladies' Association of the Union, Annual Report 1971 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Madison Hall 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Marine Science 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Capital Outlay Projection 1972-19741971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College report: Annual Budget 1972-19731971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Self-Study 1971 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - General 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Financial 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Mathematics 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Vice-President for Health Sciences 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - General 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical School - General 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical School - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical School - Admissions 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Monthly Statistical Reports 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Operating Budget and Reports 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Reports on Current Operations 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Nursing 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Monroe Foundation and Library 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Mountain Lake Conference 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Music 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - "Na" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - "Ne - Nz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - NASA 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Office for Advancement of Public Negro Colleges 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Southern Regional Legislative Committee 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - NASULGC - For your information 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - NASULGC - Circular Letters 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - NASULGC - International letters 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Defense Education Act 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Historical Publications Commission 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Science Advisory Committee for Institutional Relations 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Science Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - National Science Foundation - Institutional Grants 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - National War College 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - Naval History 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - Navy - General 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - Navy - ROTC 1971-1972 (Box 40)
  - Navy League of the U. S. 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Newcomb Hall 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Newcomen Society 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Oceanic Educational Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 41)
  - Office Invoices - 1971 1971-1972 (Box 42)
  - Office Invoices - 1972 1971-1972 (Box 42)
  - Travel Invoices - 1971-1972 1971-1972 (Box 42)
  - "P - Ph" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Personnel - General 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Personnel - Employee Relations 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Philosophy 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Physics - General 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Physics - Personnel 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Placement 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Planning Department 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Planning Division (State) 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Project Status Reports 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Provost of the University 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Psychology 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Public Affairs, Vice-President for Purchasing 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Questionnaires and Inquiries 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Radio 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Raven Society 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Recommendations "A - Z" 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Registrar - General 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Registrar - Space Reservation Request 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Registrar - Student Reports 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Rehabilitation Center 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Religious Studies 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Reports to the University Community 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - Romance Languages 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - ROTC 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - "S - Sl" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 45)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 46)
  - Salaries 1971-1972 (Box 46)
  - Security Department 1971-1972 (Box 46)
  - Senate - Faculty and University Relations Policies and Procedures 1971-1972 (Box 46)
  - Senate, University 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Seven Society 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Sociology and Anthropology 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern Fellowships Fund 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern Fellowships Fund and the Diuguid Fellowships report 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Southern University Conference 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - Special Programs (Elwood) 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - Speech and Drama 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - Speeches 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - Sponsored Programs 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - State Board of Education 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1971-1972 (Box 48)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - State Department of Higher Education 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - Student Affairs 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - Student Affairs - Group Counseling for Individual Decision-Making: Maximizing the Effectiveness of the College Placement Service1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - Student Affairs - Preparing Counselors for the College Placement Service1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - University Flood Relief by Students and Faculty - 20-22 June 1972 1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - Student Council 1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - Student Council - First Year 1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - Student Counseling Center 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Student Health 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Student Legal Forum 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Summer Session - 1971 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Summer Session Finals - 1971 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Treasurer 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Treasurer (State) 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - Tuition and Fees 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 51)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - United States Congress 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - United States Department of Defense 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - United States Department of State 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - United Naval Academy 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Center in Virginia 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Community Relations 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Editor 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Events 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Hall 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Press of Virginia 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Printing Office 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Register 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Tuesday - 19 October 1971 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - University Union 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - Universities Research Association 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - Upward Bound 1971-1972 (Box 52)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Educational Association 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Historical Society 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Virginia Weekly 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - Visitors - General 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Buildings and Grounds 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Educational Policy Committee 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Executive Committee 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Finance Committee 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Committee on Legislature 1971-1972 (Box 55)
  - Visitors - Mary Washington College 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Medical College 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Student Affairs and Athletics 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - ad hoc Committee - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Docket, 1 October 1971 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Minutes, 1 October 1971 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Docket, 11 December 1971 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Minutes, 11 December 1971 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Docket, 3 February 1972 1971-1972 (Box 56)
  - Visitors - Minutes, 3 February 1972 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - Visitors - Docket, 7 April 1972 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - Visitors - Minutes, 7 April 1972 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - Visitors - Docket, 2 June 1972 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - Visitors - Minutes, 2 June 1972 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - "W - Wh" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 57)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Walpole Society 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Water Resources 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1971-1972 (Box 58)
- Series II: University Committees, 1971-1972
  - Committee- Administrative 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Academic Computing 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Admissions 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Architectural Advisory 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Athletic Advisory Council 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Arboretum 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Calendar Appendix, A and B 1971-1972 (Box 58)
  - Committee- Calendar, Appendix C and D 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Calendar and Scheduling 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Catalogue 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Chapel 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Community Colleges 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Danforth Fellowships 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Data Processing 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Educational Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Environment 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Extension Activities 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - Committee- Fraternities 1971-1972 (Box 59)